<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<implementation xml:lang="en" generated-datetime="2012-10-04T14:45:26+01:00">
  <metadata>
    <publisher code=""></publisher>
    <version></version>
    <date>2012-10-04</date>
  </metadata>
  <publishing>
    <scope value="0.9">
      <narrative>The data from Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MFA), Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency (Sida), Ministry of Finance and Ministry of the Environment activities will be included initially. This will cover more than 90 % of Sweden’s ODA. At a later stage all Sweden’s ODA is planned to be covered.</narrative>
    </scope>
    <publication-timetable date-initial="2011-11-01">
      <narrative>Sweden will be able to publish full IATI phase 1 data, with some exceptions (see section 4 for details), by the end of November 2011.  </narrative>
    </publication-timetable>
    <publication-frequency frequency="m" timeliness="">
      <narrative>Data will initially be published on a monthly basis. At a later stage publication could be more frequent. If we are able to meet the system requirements we will publish data (nonetheless subject to change due to quality assurance) in real time.</narrative>
    </publication-frequency>
    <publication-lifecycle point="i">
      <narrative>Project data and documentation will be published for all contributions that are under implementation or completed. We will also publish data but most likely no documentation for contributions that are in pipeline.  </narrative>
    </publication-lifecycle>
    <data-quality quality="v">
      <narrative>Contribution information and disbursements are actual information from Sida’s business system and likely to remain as it is. In other words they are reasonably verified at the time of publication. Data is however subject to change if there is just cause. Forecasts are unverified.  </narrative>
    </data-quality>
    <approach resource="d">
      <narrative>Sida is responsible for publishing and coordination of Swedish IATI data. Pursuing IATI is a cross departmental effort, where the main responsibility lays in the department of Communications and Corporate management. The ambition is having a seamless solution, that is, publishing data with IATI won´t require further efforts from anyone who is not directly involved with the IATI implementation and system building. Programme Officers are responsible for the data and documentation for their activities. Policy directions are led by the Communications department and are backed up by Sweden’s Aid Transparency Guarantee, which includes the IATI ambitions.  </narrative>
    </approach>
    <notes>
      <narrative></narrative>
    </notes>
    <thresholds>
      <narrative>No thresholds will be applicable. Data for all Sida activities active at some point 2010 or later will be published, while data from the Ministry for Foreign Affairs will be available from 2011 and forward. In case that documentation can be connected to activities these will be published as well.</narrative>
    </thresholds>
    <exclusions>
      <narrative>No exclusions will be made to data. The data for classified activities will be aggregated and classified under "Global" and all other categories will be "unspecified". The documentation for these activities will not be included. Documentation will be available for all activities if matches can be found as long as they do not include classified or person sensitive information.

An activity is identified as sensitive based on the following four categories.

i. International relations: Information that may harm Sweden's relations with other governments or institutions.
ii. Security and safety: Information that may pose a risk to the security or safety of any individual, staff, contractor or beneficiary.
iii. Personal information: Information that intrudes on the privacy of a person or could contravene confidentiality.
iv. Business relations: Information that may harm business relations.</narrative>
    </exclusions>
    <constraints-other>
      <narrative>It won't be possible to deliver on all entries required by IATI as they are not captured in the present project management system.</narrative>
    </constraints-other>
    <license license="p">
      <narrative>Sweden allows use and reuse of the activity data information free of charge in any format or medium, thus meeting the IATI licensing policy. Documentation, however, cannot be used freely since Sida in many cases does not hold copyright.</narrative>
    </license>
    <activity-multilevel yesno="y">
      <narrative>Every contribution (aka activities) has at least one component. Some components are broken down into sub-components (by forms of distribution). All this information will be published.     </narrative>
    </activity-multilevel>
    <segmentation segmentation="b">
      <narrative>Sweden will publish data in files segmented by country, region, multilateral organisation and globally. This may not be optimal for those seeking information about our partner countries as approximately 10% of our components are active in more than one country, standing for about 15% of the disbursements.  </narrative>
    </segmentation>
    <user-interface status="i">
      <narrative>No additional interface will be provided to raw IATI data for the time being. However, data and documentation on Sweden’s ODA can be browsed with a user friendly interface on www.openaid.se. The portal is not completely user friends. It is entirely in Swedish, the data is not fully IATI compatible and there is no easy way to export data. It is already under discussion to solve these limitations. Nevertheless at writing moment there is no timeframe for this work.</narrative>
    </user-interface>
  </publishing>
  <organisation>
    <total-budget>
      <status category="pc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions category="d">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Will be able to publish budgets for planned and agreed contributions.</notes>
    </total-budget>
    <recipient-org-budget>
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="c">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Will not be able to publish.</notes>
    </recipient-org-budget>
    <recipient-country-budget>
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="c">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Will not be able to publish budgets on country level.</notes>
    </recipient-country-budget>
    <document-link>
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="c">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Country strategies are available but we cannot add links in the IATI feeds at the moment.</notes>
    </document-link>
  </organisation>
  <activity>
    <reporting-org>
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Will be Sida</notes>
    </reporting-org>
    <iati-identifier>
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
    </iati-identifier>
    <other-identifier>
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="a">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Not relevant with other identifiers</notes>
    </other-identifier>
    <title type="agency">
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Mostly in English</notes>
    </title>
    <title type="recipient">
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="c">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>For the time being only Swedish and English titles will be published</notes>
    </title>
    <description type="agency">
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Mostly in English</notes>
    </description>
    <description type="recipient">
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="c">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>For the time being only Swedish and English descriptions will be published</notes>
    </description>
    <activity-status>
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
    </activity-status>
    <activity-date type="start">
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
    </activity-date>
    <activity-date type="end">
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
    </activity-date>
    <contact-info>
      <status category="pc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Only Sida's activity contacts will be published at the time being.</notes>
    </contact-info>
    <participating-org type="funding">
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Sweden</notes>
    </participating-org>
    <participating-org type="extending">
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>MFA, Sida or other government organisation.</notes>
    </participating-org>
    <participating-org type="implementing">
      <status category="uc"/>
      <exclusions category="d">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>The quality of this data is too low and as the time being requires too much manual work to be able to publish it every month. We are trying to correct this.</notes>
    </participating-org>
    <participating-org type="accountable">
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <provider-definition>Agreement partner</provider-definition>
      <notes>We only record the details for the 1st level of implementation (i.e. Who we directly give our money to). There may be further organisations in the chain (e.g. A management agent further distributing funds to NGOs, contractors, etc.) which we currently do not record.</notes>
    </participating-org>
    <recipient-country>
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
    </recipient-country>
    <recipient-region>
      <status category="uc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions category="d">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>The quality is not great for this field, the regions are not completely the same when comparing Sida's definitions to the IATI definitions.</notes>
    </recipient-region>
    <location>
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="c">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>This data is not registered in our systems for the time being.</notes>
    </location>
    <sector type="crs">
      <status category="pc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions category="d">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Sweden follows a CRS sector structure, with some deviations.</notes>
    </sector>
    <sector type="agency">
      <status category="fc"/>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Sweden has only two donor specific sector codes.</notes>
    </sector>
    <policy-marker>
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
    </policy-marker>
    <collaboration-type>
      <status category="uc"/>
      <exclusions category="d">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>This data is of low quality and requires too much manual work for publishing on a monthly basis. We are trying to correct this.</notes>
    </collaboration-type>
    <default-flow-type>
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Only ODA activities will be published at the moment.</notes>
    </default-flow-type>
    <default-finance-type>
      <status category="pc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions category="c">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>This data is retrieved from another system and can only be registered once a year.</notes>
    </default-finance-type>
    <default-aid-type>
      <status category="uc"/>
      <exclusions category="d">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>The data is of low quality and requires too much manual work for publishing on a monthly basis. We are trying to correct this.</notes>
    </default-aid-type>
    <default-tied-status>
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="d">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>This data is of low quality.</notes>
    </default-tied-status>
    <budget>
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Aggregated on a higher hierarchical level.</notes>
    </budget>
    <planned-disbursement>
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
    </planned-disbursement>
    <transaction type="commitment">
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Only yearly commitments will be published.</notes>
    </transaction>
    <transaction type="disbursement">
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>All transactions will be published, however aggregated for the year / period for the time being.</notes>
    </transaction>
    <transaction type="reimbursement">
      <status category="pc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions category="d">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>All transactions are aggregated for the year and it will not be possible to distinguish expenditures from reimbursements.</notes>
    </transaction>
    <transaction type="incoming">
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="c">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Not captured.</notes>
    </transaction>
    <transaction type="repayment">
      <status category="pc"/>
      <exclusions category="d">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Loan and interest are only updated once a year.</notes>
    </transaction>
    <document-link>
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
    </document-link>
    <activity-website>
      <status category="pc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>All activities can be accessed on www.openaid.se</notes>
    </activity-website>
    <related-activity>
      <status category="fc"/>
      <publication-date>2011-10-01</publication-date>
      <exclusions>
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>All contributions and components under the same agreement will be listed.</notes>
    </related-activity>
    <conditions type="attached">
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="a">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
    </conditions>
    <conditions type="text">
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="a">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
    </conditions>
    <result>
      <status category="up"/>
      <exclusions category="c">
        <narrative></narrative>
      </exclusions>
      <notes>Results data has not been identified and/or is not captured in our systems for the time being.</notes>
    </result>
  </activity>
</implementation>

